# Ian Lindley, MASc., EIT

Phone Number: 416-899-5685 E-mail: <u>ilindley@ryerson.ca</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindleyian/

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To bring my previous experience in the engineering and academic fields to a positive work environment where my unique skills in problem solving and team coordination can be used on projects that will challenge me and provide opportunities to develop new skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Master of Applied Science, Civil Engineering, Ryerson University, June 2019
  Thesis Topic: Road Safety Treatment Effects involving use of Excel and ArcGIS
- Bachelor of Engineering., Civil Engineering, Ryerson University, June 2017
  Capstone Topic: Traffic Impact Study involving use of Synchro and AutoCAD

#### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

# January 2018 - April 2019

Ryerson University

#### **Graduate Assistant**

Toronto, ON

- Organized and led tutorials on the application of theory, Synchro software and InterCalc software
- Courses focused on Highway Design and Traffic Operations
- Marked assignments and tests correctly and in reasonable time

# May - August 2017

Toronto Zenith Contracting Ltd.

# Student Estimator

Concord, ON

- Used HeavyBid and WinEst to assist in bid estimation
- Communicated with subcontractors ensuring the accuracy of bids
- Implemented asset tracking program and trained staff in its use

#### May – August 2016

Region of Peel

#### **Student Inspector – Operations Support: Connections Section**

Brampton, ON

- Inspected water and sanitary connections between private projects and regional infrastructure
- Coordinated with private contractors, residents and government officials on work being completed such as pressure tests and watermain shutdowns
- Ensured work complied to Safety and regional standards

May – August 2015 Region of Peel

# **Student Inspector – Operations Support: Capital Works Section**

Brampton, ON

- Inspected watermain, sanitary main and culvert construction projects
- Provided support to Regional Inspector by working with contractors on site
- Took accurate measurements, such as watermain depth, ensuring regional standards

May – August 2014 Student Materials Tester – Operations Support

- Region of Peel Brampton, ON
- Conducted lab tests including sieve analysis, proctor test and concrete strength tests
- Used nuclear density gauge to test soil properties in the field
- Field concrete testing including air and slump
- Underwent specialized training in the transportation of dangerous goods and vehicle operation

## EXTRACIRRUCULAR ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

# **September 2017 – June 2019**

Ryerson University

## **Institute of Transportation Engineers (ITE) – Ryerson Chapter President**

Toronto, ON

- Planned student events, managed executive committee and coordinated with other student chapters, ITE and Ryerson University
- Secured funding for Traffic Bowl competition teams
- Competed in annual Traffic Bowl competition at the CITE annual conference in Toronto (2017), Edmonton (2018) and Ottawa (2019). Finished in 2<sup>nd</sup> place in Edmonton.

January 2019 Ryerson University

#### Transportation Research Board (TRB) Author and Presenter

Toronto, ON

- Co-Author on paper submitted to TRB
- Presenter at Annual Meeting in Washington, D.C.

November 2016 Ryerson University

#### **Ryerson Engineering Competition Contestant**

Toronto, ON

- Presented arguments on both sides of various topics such as logistics and climate change
- Finished 3<sup>rd</sup> in Parliamentary Debate

#### **September 2014 – March 2015**

**Ryerson University** 

# Ryerson Concrete Toboggan Team Member

Toronto, ON

- Competed at GNCTR 2015 in Kelowna, BC
- Earned awards for display and concrete mix design